Dwayne Winter

CAPABILITY STATEMENT:

Enthusiastic, hardworking and a professional individual, I am willing and eager to utilize and expand my knowledge base. I have obtained a sound theoretical and practical skill set earned through a combination of university and workforce experience.

KEY ACHIEVEMENTS & EXPERIENCE:

Rio Tinto Iron Ore

QA/QC Chemist

July 2014 - Present

In this role it is my responsibility to assist on-site Laboratories with any technical issues or improvements relating but not limited to analytical methods, QA/QC programs, process control, IS&T, and data reporting via LIMS or satellite applications. I also provide input into the design of new Laboratories, and/or expansion of current Laboratories, along with imparting technical knowledge to on-site Laboratory staff and various customers whom the Laboratory services. I report to the Specialist Lab and Sampling.

Experience:

Training

- Attended a course on the basic use of Spotfire.
- Attended several sessions with a programmer fluent in the language used by STARLIMS.
- First Aid

Responsibilities

- The ability to multi-task.
- Identifying and understanding inconsistencies in results in order to correct issues and suggest improvements to prevent re-occurrences.
- Developing and maintaining new programs for XRF, Fusion, and TGA analysis.
- Perform various modifications to XRF applications to adjust for drift and other affects.
- Troubleshooting various errors associated with instrument computers.
- Identifying areas of improvement within on-site Laboratories processes.
- Working and communicating well with on-site Laboratory staff in order to provide assistance where required.
- Delivering presentations to site personnel to assist with the understanding of the technical aspects of Sampling, Sample Preparation, and Analysis within the Laboratory.
- Development and configuration of STARLIMS, and its deployment to on-site Laboratories
- Fixing bugs and implementing improvements in the STARLIMS and CCLAS process flow.
- Improving the STARLIMS application and database performance and reliability.
- Developing new and updating existing guides to performing tasks in LIMS (SPL's).
- Developing new and updating existing Spotfire, SSRS, and Crystal Reports to provide Laboratory personnel and other key stakeholders with key metrics and information pertaining to but not limited to Laboratory performance and sample lifecycles.
- Providing input into the design of new Laboratories, expansion of existing Laboratories, and improvement of existing Sample Stations and Laboratories.
- Investigating the application of new technologies.
- Addressing queries pertaining to quality and/or Laboratory capabilities and limitations.

- Attending meetings as a member of the MN-002-02 Iron Ore committee so as to be upto-date with developments within the industry, and drive development work that is both in the interest of the company and the wider Iron Ore community.
- Conducting test work on-site to contribute towards method and/or standard development within the Australian Iron Ore committee.
- Communicating to on-site personnel the application of ISO standards as well as best practices.
- Working with key stakeholders in the IS&T department to ensure the Laboratories requirements are met and maintained
- Liaising with vendors to the Laboratory to ensure Laboratory requirements are met and concerns are addressed, whilst also assisting the vendor with navigating the processes and pathways within the Company so as they can deliver the service required.
- Working with key stakeholders in the Technical Marketing/Commercial departments of the Company to investigate non-compliances and interrogate data.

Achievements

- A member of the MN-002 Iron Ore standards committee.
- 7x replaced a Laboratories CCLAS software with STARLIMS
- 1x commissioned a new Laboratory

SGS Australia

XRF Chemist January 2009 – July 2014

In this role it is my responsibility to QC and report results obtained from the fusion and TGA process, train QA/QC staff on correct Quality Control techniques, develop and maintain XRF calibrations, and address any technical queries or issues that arise during day to day operations. I report to the XRF Manager and the Geochem-Minerals Lab Manager.

Experience:

Training

- Completed a course on Radiation Safety and received my radiation license for X-ray Analysis-Use and Service (restricted).
- Attended a Frontline Management Course.
- Completed the PANalytical Willis & Duncan course on advanced XRF Spectrometry.

Responsibilities

- The ability to work efficiently whilst maintaining high quality and high productivity.
- Prioritizing various tasks so as to meet deadlines.
- Identifying and understanding inconsistencies in results so as they can be reprocessed or corrected.
- Identifying recurring errors or inaccuracies and rectifying them.
- Checking and replenishing various consumables used in the laboratory practices.
- Performing monthly back-ups and data purges on TGA and XRF computers.
- Developing new programs for XRF and TGA analysis.
- Troubleshooting various errors associated with any of the computers used in the XRF department.
- Troubleshooting various errors associated with robotics systems.
- Identifying areas of improvement within the robotics and manual process streams and providing potential solutions.
- Working and communicating well with the XRF management team to ensure that any problems are addressed in a timely fashion.
- Perform routine safety checks on XRF instruments as acting Radiation Safety Officer (RSO).
- Create/Update jobs booked in for the XRF technique.

- Maintain/Update profiling procedures for various clients.
- Perform various modifications to XRF applications to adjust for drift and other affects.
- Performing interviews for potential employees.
- Providing assistance to remote site operations.
- Developing and implementing new work procedures.
- Ensuring procedures are followed and kept up to date.
- Addressing client queries pertaining to quality and/or XRF capabilities and limitations.
- Attending meetings as a member of the MN-002-02 Iron Ore committee so as to be up-to-date with developments within the industry.
- Monitoring quality through semi and fully automated systems for both XRF and TGA

Achievements

- NATA accredited for XRF (Iron Ores).
- Cert IV in Frontline Management.
- A member of the MN-002 Iron Ore standards committee.

SGS Australia

XRF QC April 2008 – January 2009

In this role it was my responsibility to QC and report results obtained from the fusion and TGA process. I report to the XRF Manager and the Production Supervisor.

Experience:

Responsibilities

- The ability to work efficiently whilst maintaining high quality and high productivity.
- Prioritizing various jobs so as to meet deadlines.
- Identifying and understanding inconsistencies in results so as they can be reprocessed or corrected.
- Bringing recurring errors or inaccuracy's to the attention of the appropriate people.
- Maintaining and cleaning fusion equipment.
- Performing monthly back-ups and data purges on TGA and XRF computers.
- · Adjusting and monitoring fusion equipment.
- Troubleshooting various errors associated with any of the computers used in the XRF department.
- Working and communicating well with my fellow colleagues to ensure that productivity was maintained during day to day operations.
- Filed and maintained service records for XRF instruments.
- Created/Updated jobs booked in for the XRF technique.
- Training new staff in how to perform the various tasks within the laboratory.

SGS Australia

XRF Technician July 2007 – April 2008

In this role it was my responsibility to prepare samples for fusion and to analyse samples via Thermo-Gravimetric Analysis (TGA) and X-Ray Fluorescence (XRF). I reported to the XRF Manager and the Production Supervisor.

Responsibilities

- The ability to work efficiently whilst maintaining a high quality and a high productivity.
- Ensuring that my work area was kept clean and tidy at all times.
- Working and communicating well with my fellow colleagues to ensure that productivity was maintained during the shift rotations.

Curriculum Vitae - Dwayne Winter

- Moving samples in/out of the lab as required.
- Operating LECO 701-1 and 601-1 TGA machines.
- Weighing samples and flux.
- Operating fusion machines. (Phoenix 6000 models)
- Operating press powder machines.
- Operating XRF equipment. XRF instruments range from the X'Unique II, through to the Axios, Magix Fast, and the PW2400.

Kennedy Drilling

Manager.

Drillers Offsider Dec 2003 – Feb 2004 In this role I assisted the driller in the operation of the drill rig. I reported to the Driller and

Responsibilities

- The ability to work efficiently and maintain a high productivity.
- Separating each metre of dirt into piles away from the drill rig to avoid contamination.
- Lifting drilling rods onto the drilling platform.
- Clearing shrubs and bushes to facilitate a safer work environment.
- Partaking in various camping duties whilst in the bush.

UNIVERSITY EDUCATION:

Curtin University - Perth, Western Australia

Bachelor of Science (Physics) (Minor in Chemistry) - 2003-2006.

My physics degree consisted of a wide variety of courses, ranging from Electromagnetism to Astrophysics. I also challenged myself by taking complex courses such as Solid State Physics and Quantum Mechanics. Along the way I also built on my laboratory practices by undertaking various chemistry orientated subjects. Consequently my time at Curtin University imparted me with the ability to extract information and to problem solve various analytical and technical issues. In addition my lab based abilities were cultivated and I gained good lab practices.

TAFE EDUCATION:

North Metro Tafe - Perth, Western Australia

Ongoing - Certificate IV in IT (Programming) - 2023-present.

I am currently undertaking study in this course, working towards a Certificate IV in IT (Programming). In this course, I have been exposed to various programming languages including Python, Javascript, C++, and web design. The course also delved into SQL database querying, CyberSecurity, and collaboration skills and technologies.

IT SKILLS:

- Proficient with the use of Microsoft Word, Excel, PowerPoint and Outlook
- Proficient with PANalytical's SuperQ Software

- Proficient with LECO Software
- Proficient with the use of STARLIMS Database Software and capable of major scripting alterations and design.
- Proficient with the design and use of Spotfire Reports
- Proficient with the design and use of SSRS Reports
- Proficient with the design and use of Crystal Reports
- Proficient with querying SQL and Oracle Databases
- Capable of navigating and minor scripting alterations with LIMS CCLAS Database Software

| REFERENCES: | |
|--|--|
| Use the 'Contact' page to request references | |
| | |
| | |
| | |
| | |
| | |
| | |
| | |
| | |
| | |
| | |
| | |
| | |
| | |
| | |
| | |